eharmony.co.uk 2018-12-24

# eHarmony Privacy Policy

## General Information

**Welcome to eHarmony! At eHarmony ("we", "us", "our") we value your privacy and trust, so we’re providing you with all the information in this Privacy Policy about how we handle your data, who we share it with, your rights around the data, and our company, as well as our products and applications (including eHarmony's mobile applications, downloadable products and applications and pages operated by eHarmony on social networking sites and other platforms) (collectively, the "Services").**

This Privacy Policy applies beginning May 25, 2018. The previous version of this Privacy Policy, available here, will apply until then.

**EFFECTIVE DATE: 25 May 2018.**

For the purposes of EU data protection laws (" **Data Protection Legislation** "), eHarmony UK Ltd is the data controller (i.e. the company which is responsible for, and controls the processing of, your personal data)

* * *

## 1\. Where this Privacy Policy applies

This Privacy Policy applies to websites, apps, events and other services operated by eHarmony. For simplicity, we refer to all of these as our " **Service** " in this Privacy Policy.

Some services may require their own unique privacy policy. If a particular service has its own privacy policy, then that policy - not this Privacy Policy - applies.

## 2\. What Information We Collect

We may collect, use, store and transfer different kinds of personal data about you which we have grouped together follows: 

  * **Information You Provide**. When you register, use or subscribe to any of our Services or take part in any interactive features of the Services (such as any contests, games, promotions, quizzes, surveys, research or other services or features), we may collect a variety of information, including: 
    * **"Contact Data"** such as your name, email address, and phone number 
    * **"Profile Data"**. " when you complete your profile, you can share with us additional information, such as details on your personality, lifestyle, interests, demographic information, place of work or education, gender, age, dating age range preference, physical characteristics, personal description, life experiences, geographic location and other details about you, as well as content such as photos and videos. To add certain content, like pictures or videos (" **Photos** "), you may allow us to access your camera or photo album. Some of the information you choose to provide us may be considered "special" or "sensitive" in certain jurisdictions, for example your racial or ethnic origins, sexual orientation and religious beliefs. **By choosing to provide this information, you consent to our processing of that information.**
    * **"Transaction Data"**. such as when you subscribe to a paid service or make a purchase directly from us, you provide us or our payment service provider with information, such as your debit or credit card number or other financial information including, for example, expiration date, name, address, transaction ID, timestamps, and email address. Credit card transactions are processed through industry standard Secure Socket Layer (SSL) and / or strong encryption (3DES) by a third party, which only uses your information for that purpose. 
    * **Information from Content You Upload**. When you upload photos, videos or other content to the Services, we may collect information about the content, such as the time, date and place the photo or content was taken or uploaded (also known as metadata), and how you use them, who views them or with whom you share. We may also scan and analyse the photos you provide to us using third party services for several purposes, including for anti-fraud purposes, for the assessment of whether the photos are consistent with our Terms of Service, to help identify your interests and activities, such as if your photo includes pets, sports, or trips, and to help us provide better matches for you. 
    * **"Communications Data"**. if you contact our customer care team, we will collect the information you give us during the interaction. Sometimes, we monitor or record these interactions for training purposes and to ensure a high quality of service. Of course, we also process your chats with other users as well as the content you publish, as part of the operation of the Services. 
    * When you participate in surveys or focus groups, you give us your insights into our products and services, responses to our questions and testimonials. 
    * When you choose to participate in our promotions, events or contests, we collect the information that you use to register or enter. 
    * Where you choose to disclose your comments in the comments section (if any) of our Advice blog. Our Advice blog is made up of posts that are relevant to dating and relationships and is available to our users and visitors. Please consult our Community Guidelines when posting comments on the Advice discussion boards. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us at [eHadvicealerts@eHarmony.co.uk](mailto:eHadvicealerts@eHarmony.co.uk). 
  * **Information Automatically Collected**. When you access our Services, we and our third party partners automatically record information from your device and its software, such as your IP address, browser type, Internet service provider, platform type, the site from which you came and the site to which you are going when you leave our website, date and time stamp and one or more cookies that may uniquely identify your browser or your account. When you access our Services using a mobile device, we may also receive or collect identification numbers associated with your device (such as a unique device ID, IDFA, Google AdID), device type, model and manufacturer, mobile device operating system brand and model, phone number, email address, and other apps that you have downloaded (" **Technical Data** "). We also collect information about your usage of, and activity on, our Services (" **Usage Data** "). 
  * **Information About How You Use the Services**. We may collect information about your participation and actions on the Services. This may include information such as the pages and profiles you view, how you browse the Services and dating insights. It can also include the various functions and features that you use, the connections you make, other friends or contacts you invite to the Services and profile searches you perform, or your use of our applications. 
  * **Location Data**. We do not currently collect your precise geolocation or any latitude or longitude coordinates for you. Some of the information we collect, for example an IP address, can sometimes be used to approximate a device’s location. In some cases, we assign the latitude and longitude of the centre of a city or state on record for you to your profile as a way to improve our analytics and matches for you. This is a general latitude and longitude and does not correspond to your real time or historical location specifically. 
  * **Information Provided by Others**. We may be provided with information relating to you or your conduct on the Services by other users of the Services. For example, we will collect your email address if another user tries to refer eHarmony to you. We also collect information that third-party organizations may provide to us, such as contact details, demographic information, Internet navigation details (for example, how your mouse moves on a screen, which tells us if you are a bot or not) or fraud prevention information. Financial institutions or payment processors may also provide us updated payment information or payment methods related to your paid account or paid subscription and services. 

We may link or combine the personal data we collect about you and the information we collect automatically. This allows us to provide you with a personalised experience regardless of how you interact with us.

We may anonymise and aggregate any of the personal data we collect (so that it does not directly identify you). We may use anonymised information for our business purposes including testing our IT systems, research, data analysis, improving our Services and developing new products and features. We may also share such anonymised information with others.

Where you do not provide the personal data detailed in this Privacy Policy, we may not be able to provide you with the Services.

## 3\. How We Collect and Use Information

The main reason we use your information is to deliver and improve our Services. Additionally, we use your information to help keep you safe and to provide you with advertising that may be of interest to you.

Generally, we will use your personal data in the following circumstances:

  * Where we need to perform the contract we are about to enter into or have entered into with you for the Services. 
  * Where you have given consent for us to use your personal data and your sensitive personal data to provide certain Services. (You may withdraw your consent for some uses of the data at any time by contacting us.) 
  * Where it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) and your interests and fundamental rights do not override those interests. 
  * Where we need to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation. 

## 4\. Purposes For Which We Will Use Your Personal Data

We have set out in the table below a description of all the ways we plan to use your personal data, and which of the legal bases we rely on to do so. Please contact us if you need details about the specific legal basis we are relying on to process your personal data where more than one legal basis has been set out.

Purpose/Activity | Type of data   
(defined in Section 2 above) | Lawful basis for processing including basis of legitimate interest  
---|---|---  
To register you as a new member | 

  * Profile Data 
  * Contact Data 
  * Technical Data 

| To process your personal, we rely on the following legal bases: 

  * To provide our Service to you 
  * With your consent in the case of sensitive personal data 

To provide the Services to you, including: 

  * Maintaining a profile, answering questions, and providing information about yourself. 
  * Analysing your personal data to match you with other users. 
  * Allowing you to communicate with other users of eHarmony to make a match. 
  * Enabling you to purchase subscriptions and premium add-ons to enhance your opportunities to make a match with other eHarmony users. 

| 

  * Profile Data 
  * Contact Data 
  * Photos 
  * Communications Data 
  * Usage Data 
  * Technical Data 
  * Transaction Data 
  * Analytics and other scores used to make matches with other eHarmony users 

|  To process your personal, we rely on the following legal bases: 

  * To provide our Service to you 
  * With your consent in the case of sensitive personal data 
  * Necessary for our legitimate interests (in order to improve our Service) 

To manage our relationship with you which will include: 

  * Notifying you about changes to our terms or privacy policy 
  * Communicate with you. 

| 

  * Profile Data 
  * Contact Data 
  * Transaction Data 
  * Communications Data 
  * Photos 
  * Usage Data 

|  To process your personal, we rely on the following legal bases: 

  * To provide our Service to you 
  * Necessary to comply with a legal obligation 

To enable you to partake in a prize draw, competition or complete a survey | 

  * Profile Data 
  * Contact Data 
  * Usage Data 
  * Any information, content, or submissions required as set force in the contest rules when published 

|  To process your personal, we rely on the following legal bases: 

  * To provide our Service to you 
  * Necessary for our legitimate interests (to study how customers use our Services, to develop them and grow our business) 

To administer and protect our business, the Services, our website and your personal data (including security, fraud, troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, system maintenance, support, reporting and hosting of data)  | 

  * Profile Data 
  * Contact Data 
  * Technical Data 
  * Usage Data 
  * Communications Data 
  * Third Party Data provided to us by trusted partners, including proprietary scores, red flags, demographic information, usage data, and other information used to determine whether a eHarmony account is being used improperly, accessed by an unauthorized third party, or represents a security or fraud risk to the eHarmony community 

| To process your personal, we rely on the following legal bases: 

  * Necessary for our legitimate interests (for running our business, provision of administration and IT services, cybersecurity, to prevent fraud and in the context of a business reorganisation or group restructuring exercise) 
  * Necessary to comply with a legal obligation 

To deliver relevant website content and advertisements to you and measure or understand the effectiveness of the advertising we serve to you | 

  * Device ID 
  * IP Address 
  * Location (at country, state, city or postal code level) 
  * Gender 
  * Age 
  * Technical Data 
  * Cookies, pixels or advertising tags 
  * Usage Data 

|  To process your personal, we rely on the following legal basis: 

  * Necessary for our legitimate interests (to study how customers use our products/services, to develop them, to grow our business and to inform our marketing strategy) 

To use data analytics to improve our website, products/services, marketing, customer relationships and experiences | 

  * Profile Data 
  * Usage Data 
  * Technical Data 

|  To process your personal, we rely on the following legal basis: 

  * Necessary for our legitimate interests (to define types of customers for our products and services, to keep our website updated and relevant, to develop our business and to inform our marketing strategy) 

To respond to requests from law enforcement | 

  * Profile Data 
  * Transaction Data 
  * Usage Data 
  * Communications Data 
  * Location Data (at country, state, city, or postal code level) 
  * Technical Data, such as IP Address or Device ID 
  * Any other information we are compelled to provide by law 

|  To process your personal, we rely on the following legal basis: 

  * Necessary to comply with our legal obligations 

## 5\. Marketing

From time to time we may contact you with relevant information about our Services. Most messages we send will be by email. For some messages, we may use personal data we collect about you to help us determine the most relevant information to share with you.

If you do not want to receive such messages from us, you will be able to tell us by selecting certain boxes on forms we use when we first collect your contact details. You can change your marketing preferences by clicking on the unsubscribe link at the bottom of our emails. You can also opt-out of receiving promotional emails and newsletters by clicking on " **My Settings** " option on your eHarmony home page, choosing the " **Email Settings** " link and un-checking the undesired promotions.

## 6\. Disclosure of Your Information to Third Parties

Our Services allow you to share information about yourself with other individuals and other companies, including other users and potential users of the Services or other products or services offered by eHarmony. Consider your own privacy and personal safety when sharing your information with anyone, including information you share through your profile.

We may have to share your personal data with the parties set out below for the purposes in the table above.

  * With other entities within the eHarmony group of companies (namely eHarmony Inc.) in order to provide you with the Services. 
  * Disclosure to Protect Abuse Victims. We reserve the right, but have no obligation, to disclose any information that you submit to the Services, if in our sole opinion, we suspect or have reason to suspect, that the information involves a party who may be the victim of abuse in any form. Abuse may include, without limitation, elder abuse, child abuse, spousal abuse, neglect, or domestic violence. Information may be disclosed to authorities that we, in our sole discretion, deem appropriate to handle such disclosure. Appropriate authorities may include, without limitation, law enforcement agencies, child protection agencies, or court officials. You hereby acknowledge and agree that we are permitted to make such disclosure. 
  * Technology Services Providers, including infrastructure partners (such as AWS), customer support service providers, analytics service providers, cybersecurity partners, fraud analytics companies, payment providers, chargeback representation services and similar partners. 
  * Advertising networks and technology companies that measure advertising performance and attribution. 
  * Third parties, including consultants, who we engage to provide services on our behalf or to jointly provide services to you, including but not limited to contests and sweepstakes, marketing outreach and analytics, customer support, safety checks, and payment services (such as Cyber Source). 
  * Social Networks, such as Facebook, where you have given permission to do so or where you have used your social network account to log-in to eHarmony. If you have chosen to do this, your data will be governed by the privacy policy of that social network. 
  * To, in our discretion, (i) satisfy any applicable law, regulation, subpoena/court order, legal process or other government request, (ii) enforce our Terms of Service, including the investigation of potential violations thereof, (iii) investigate and defend ourselves against any third party claims or allegations, (iv) protect against harm to the rights, property or safety of eHarmony, its users or the public as required or permitted by law and (v) detect, prevent or otherwise address criminal (including fraud or stalking), security or technical issues. 
  * In connection with any company transaction, such as a merger, sale of assets or shares, reorganization, financing, change of control or acquisition of all or a portion of our business by another company or third party or in the event of bankruptcy, dissolution, divestiture or any related or similar proceedings; and 
  * We require all third parties to respect the security and privacy of your personal data and to treat it in accordance with the law. The majority of the third parties we share your personal data with are service providers that are permitted to process your personal data for specified purposes and in accordance with our instructions only. Some third parties will process your personal data for their own purposes as data controllers; please refer to their privacy policy which applies to their processing of your personal data. We are not responsible for those third parties. 

## 7\. International Transfers

The personal data we collect may be transferred to, and processed and stored in, countries outside of the jurisdiction you are in where we and our third party service providers have operations. If you are located in the European Union ("EU"), your personal data may be processed outside of the EU, including, for example, in the United States; these international transfers of your personal data are made:

  * to a country or territory ensuring an adequate level of protection for the rights and freedoms of data subjects in relation to the processing of personal data as determined by the European Commission; or 
  * to a the third party that is a member of a compliance scheme recognised as offering adequate protection for the rights and freedoms of data subjects as determined by the European Commission; or 
  * pursuant to appropriate safeguards, such as the Standard Contractual Clauses (processors) approved by European Commission Decision C(2010)593 or any subsequent version thereof released by the European Commission or the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield. 

If you wish to enquire further about these safeguards used, please contact us using the details set out at the end of this Privacy Policy.

## 8\. Data Security

We have extensive security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information stored in our database. These measures include the use of Secure Socket Layer (SSL) and/or strong encryption (3DES) technology during credit card transactions and administrative access to site data as well as other proprietary security measures which are applied to all repositories and transfers of user information. We will exercise reasonable care in providing secure transmission of information between your computer and our servers, but given that no information transmitted over the Internet can be guaranteed 100% secure, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information transmitted to us over the Internet and hence accept no liability for any unintentional disclosure.

## 9\. Data Retention

We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for (as set out above), including for the purpose of satisfying and legal, accounting, or reporting requirements.

To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data, and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements.

## 11\. Cookies and Similar Technologies

You may have certain rights under applicable data protection laws in relation to your personal data. You have the right to: 

  * The Service uses cookies and similar technologies to distinguish you from other users of the Service. This helps us to provide you with a good experience when you browse the Service and also allows us to improve the Service. 
  * Cookies are pieces of code that allow for personalisation of the Service experience by saving your information such as user ID and other preferences. A cookie is a small data file that we transfer to your device's hard disk (such as your computer or smartphone) for record-keeping purposes. Please follow this link to view our Cookie Policy.
  * We use the following types of cookies: 
    * **Strictly necessary cookies**. These are cookies that are required for the essential operation of the Service such as to authenticate users and prevent fraudulent use. 
    * **Analytical/performance cookies**. These allow us to recognise and count the number of visitors and to see how visitors move around the Service when they are using it. This helps us to improve the way the Service works, for example, by ensuring that users are finding what they are looking for easily. 
    * **Functionality cookies**. These are used to recognise you when you return to the Service. This enables us to personalise our content for you, greet you by name and remember your preferences (for example, your choice of language or region). 
    * **Targeting cookies**. These cookies record your visit to our website, the pages you have visited and the links you have followed. We will use this information to make our website and the advertising displayed on it, and the marketing messages we send to you more relevant to your interests. We may also share this information with third parties who provide a service to us for this purpose. 
    * **Third party cookies**. Please be aware that advertisers and other third parties may use their own cookies tags when you click on an advertisement or link on our website. These third parties are responsible for setting out their own cookie and privacy policies. 
  * The cookies we use are designed to help you get the most from the Service but if you do not wish to receive cookies, most browsers allow you to change your cookie settings. Please note that if you choose to refuse cookies you may not be able to use the full functionality of the Service. These settings will typically be found in the “ **options** ” or “ **preferences** ” menu of your browser. In order to understand these settings, the following links may be helpful, otherwise you should use the “ **Help** ” option in your browser for more details. 
    * [Cookie settings in Safari web](https://support.apple.com/kb/PH5042?locale=en_GB) and [iOS.](https://support.apple.com/en-gb/HT201265)
  * We participate in interest-based advertising and use third party advertising companies to serve you targeted advertisements based on your online browsing history and your interests. To do this, we or our advertising partners may collect information about how you use or connect to our Service, or the types of other websites, social media services, content and ads that you (or others using your device) visit or view or connect to our Service. Typically, this information is collected through cookies and similar tracking technologies. 
  * If you only want to limit third party advertising cookies, you can turn such cookies off by visiting the following links (please bear in mind that there are many more companies listed on these sites than those that drop cookies via our website): 
    * Your Online Choices ( <http://www.youronlinechoices.com/> ) 
    * Network Advertising Initiative (<http://www.networkadvertising.org/>) 
    * Digital Advertising Alliance ([http://www.aboutads.info/consumers](http://www.aboutads.info/consumers/)) 
  * We also use clear gifs in HTML-based emails sent to our Customers to track which emails are opened and which links are clicked by recipients. The information allows for more accurate reporting and improvement of our Service. You can set your e-mail options to prevent the automatic downloading of images that may contain these technologies that would allow us to know whether you have accessed our e-mail and performed certain functions with it. 
  * If you would like to find out more about cookies and other similar technologies, please visit [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/) or the Network Advertising Initiative's online sources at [www.networkadvertising.org](https://www.networkadvertising.org/). 

## 12\. Links To Third Party Sites

The Service may, from time to time, contain links to and from third party services. If you follow a link to any of these services, please note that these services have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for their policies. Please check the individual policies before you submit any information to those services.

## 13\. Our Policy Towards Children

The Service is not directed at persons under 18 and we do not knowingly collect personal data from persons under 18.

## 14\. Changes To This Policy

We evaluate our privacy policies and procedures to implement improvements and refinements from time to time. Accordingly, we may update this Privacy Policy from time to time, and so you should review this page periodically. If we make material changes to this Privacy Policy, we will update the "last updated" data at the start of this Privacy Policy. Changes to this Privacy Policy are effective when they are posted on this page.

## 15\. Notice To You

If we need to provide you with information about something, whether for legal, marketing or other business related purposes, we will select what we believe is the best way to get in contact with you. We will usually do this through email or by placing a notice on the Service. The fact that we may send notices to you will not stop you from being able to opt out of certain types of contact as described in this Privacy Policy.

eHarmony.co.uk uses cookies to enhance your onsite experience. Please see our Cookie Policy for additional details. close
